Mathilde Roblot

Data Scientist

Data science and urban planning graduated, looking for a meaningful role to find creative solutions to exciting problems and have a real-life impact. Experienced with 3+ years at making geospatial and other data useable, using machine learning algorithms to deliver insights and implement action-oriented solutions.

DETAILS



🗀 Helsinki, Finland



(+358) 40 680 1523



mathilderoblot4@gmail.com



mathilde-roblot



24 ans



Driving license

SKILLS

Interpersonal Skills

Analytical and critical thinking spirit

Communication and team player Mathematical, analytical & quantitative skills

Proactive and organized Interest in solving problems

Computer/Data Analytics Skills

Python	Pandas	Scil	kit-learn
Tensorflow PostGIS pgAdmin			
SQL	ait	BI A	ArcGis
Microsoft Office AWS Spark			

LANGUAGES

French

Mother tongue

English

Fluent C1 - IELTS 7.0

German

Intermediate Level B2

INTERESTS

Running (6 half marathons) Culinary food Architecture Itinerant trips

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

nov 2021 - present

Skenariolabs, Helsinki, Finland

- Create real estate valuation and energy label models for multiple countries in a ESG-risks analytics approach
- Develope pipeline from data extraction to model deployment with Bitbucket and AWS
- Communicate analysis results and make recommendations to the team & clients

Urban Data Scientist Intern

feb 2021 - aug 2021

EP, Nantes, France

- Identified & implemented opportunities for using data from multiple urban sources
- Built predictive models related to real estate and urban rules with ArcGIS
- Developed a new application for real estate prospecting using PostGIS and MapBox

Research Intern

sep 2019 - feb 2020

Polytechnique Montréal, Montréal, Canada

• Understood & predicted carsharing membership in Montreal with a regression model using user's characteristics and urban planning modalities

EDUCATION

Master of Science In Data Science

2020 - 2021

Université de Technologie de Compiègne, Compiègne, France

Subjects included: Data mining - Machine et deep learning - Decision theory - Robust and stochastic optimization - Multi-criteria decision under uncertainties - In-depth mathematics

Master's Degree in Urban Engineering

2016 - 2021

Université de Technologie de Compiègne, Compiègne, France

Subjects included: Technical management with social and legal dimensions of buildings -Town planning and development- Modeling and construction - Network optimization

Minor: International economics - micro- and macroeconomic, accounting, international organizations and business strategy

Exchange semester in Master of Urban Spatial Planning

2018

Technische Universität Dortmund, Dortmund, Germany

PUBLICATION

Peer-Rewiewed Journal

Roblot, M., Boisjoly, G., Francesco, C., & Martin, T. (2021). Participation in Shared Mobility: An Analysis of the Influence of Walking and Public Transport Accessibility to Vehicles on Carsharing Membership in Montreal, Canada. Transportation Research Record, 03611981211032221.

Presentation

Roblot, M., Boisjoly, G., Francesco, C., & Martin, T. Vehicles on Carsharing Membership in Montreal, Canada. Poster presented at: TRB Annual Meeting; January 2021; Washington, United States

Roblot M. Accessibilité à la mobilité partagée : une analyse des modalités d'urbanisme déterminant l'adhésion au service d'autopartage. Poster presented at: RFTM; June 2021; Paris, France